bcit.ca 2013-05-25

# BCIT : : Privacy : : Important Privacy Information

## **BCIT and Protection of Personal Information**

As a public body, BCIT complies with privacy provisions of BC's [_Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_  ](http://www.bclaws.ca/EPLibraries/bclaws_new/document/ID/freeside/96165_01)(RSBC 1996 ch. 165): 

  * Personal information is collected directly from the individual about whom it relates 
  * Personal information is collected, used, and disclosed for purposes consistent with BCIT's program and service offerings 
  * Individuals have the right of access to and a right to request correction of their own personal information 
  * Personal information is retained for the time period to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected 
  * Personal information is secured from unauthorized access
  * Individuals will be notified about the purposes for which information is collected, and when information is collected for an optional use, individuals will consent to the information collection 

You may refer to BCIT's policy 6700 Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy [PDF, 168 KB], for more information.

For more information about BCIT's privacy procedures you may contact:

Manager, Privacy and Records Management  
British Columbia Institute of Technology  
3700 Willingdon Avenue  
Burnaby, B.C., Canada V5G 3H2

Telephone: 604.432.8508

## **Notification Regarding BCIT's Web Site and Personal Information**

**** As a visitor to BCIT's Web site, BCIT's Web servers automatically collect information that is essential to operating and maintaining the site's security. The information collected includes:

  * Browser type 
  * Internet service provider (ISP) name 
  * IP address 

The extent of personal information collected by BCIT's Web servers depends on the standards followed by your ISP. You may wish to contact your provider to determine the policies and practices in this regard.

BCIT's Web site contains links to third party sites, and BCIT is not responsible for the privacy provisions of those other Web sites.

Some portions of the BCIT Web site may distribute small pieces of information (called "cookies") to Web browsers to assist you when you return to specific areas on the site. If you have concerns about cookies, you can change your Web browser settings not to accept this information, or display warning messages.

When you voluntarily send electronic mail to BCIT or complete an electronic form that includes identifying information about you, BCIT will keep a record of this information so that we can respond to you.

## Update on previously reported security issue

(Dec. 31 2012)

In June of 2012, BCIT reported a security incident that could have potentially resulted in an unauthorized third party accessing personal information of certain students, staff and faculty through a computer server associated with the Student Health Services Medical Clinic at the BCIT Burnaby Campus. To date, and to the best of our knowledge, we have not had any indication that any personal information has been compromised.

To ensure the preservation of privacy standards, BCIT notified and began working with the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of BC (OIPC) regarding this matter.

The OIPC recently released a report which confirms the actions taken by BCIT were adequate and fulfilled the obligation to protect personal information under the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act. The following is an excerpt from the summary of the report’s findings and conclusions: 

> _". . .BCIT took quick and appropriate action to contain the breach. It correctly assessed the harms that might take place if this type of information were disclosed, it notified affected individuals quickly and provided them with information required to mitigate the potential threats from this disclosure. BCIT has taken the proper steps to prevent a similar breach from occurring in the future."_

For more background and detailed information on this incident please read here.

A summary of the report from the [Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner for B.C. ](http://www.oipc.bc.ca/)(Mediation Summary F12-01-MS) is available [here](http://www.oipc.bc.ca/report/mediation-summaries.aspx).
